Guide to the Carl Djerassi Papers SC0348
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Carl Djerassi papers
1952-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Djerassi, Carl
SC0348
251.25 Linear Feet
These papers primarily concern Djerassi's research in organic chemistry and include correspondence, reports, and lab notebooks on optical rotary dispersion and mass spectrometry; other research files containing correspondence, manuscripts, and reprints; reprints of Djerassi's published articles; and grant files. There are also some materials pertaining to symposia and administrative concerns of the Dept. of Chemistry at Stanford.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Carl Djerassi, 1987 - 1999; deposit by Dale Djerassi, 2015.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research. Accession ARCH-2016-009 is on deposit through 2020.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
University research scientist and industrialist, Djerassi is most famous for synthesizing the first oral contraceptive. Born in Vienna, Austria, in 1923, he emigrated to the United States in 1939. He received his B.A. in 1942 from Kenyon College and worked briefly with the Ciba Phamaceutical Company before receiving his Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin-Madison. He taught at Wayne State University in Detroit and worked at the pharmaceutical company Syntex in Mexico before joining the Stanford faculty as Professor of Chemistry in 1959. He is the author of over 1100 articles, seven books on scientific subjects, and several novels; his awards include the National Medal of Science, the Priestly Medal, the first Wolf Prize in Chemistry, and the National Medal of Technology.
Description of the Collection
These papers primarily concern Djerassi's research in organic chemistry and include correspondence, reports, and lab notebooks on optical rotary dispersion and mass spectrometry; other research files containing correspondence, manuscripts, and reprints; reprints of Djerassi's published articles; and grant files. There are also some materials pertaining to symposia and administrative concerns of the Dept. of Chemistry at Stanford.
Notebooks.; Notebooks.; Optical rotatory dispersion.; Optical rotatory dispersion.; Mass spectrometry.; Mass spectrometry.; Steroids.; Steroids.; Chemistry, Organic.; Chemistry, Organic.; Djerassi, Carl; Djerassi, Carl; Djerassi, Carl; Djerassi, Carl; Stanford University. Department of Chemistry; Djerassi, Carl; Djerassi, Carl; Djerassi, Carl; Stanford University. Department of Chemistry; Djerassi, Carl
- ORD book manuscript files and correspondence, Series 1
  - ORD Book: Miscellaneous Correspondence in Preparation of Manuscript, 1959, (includes photo) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ORD Book: Miscellaneous Correspondence in Preparation of Manuscript, 1959, (includes photo) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ORD Book: (copyrights/Permissions, 1959) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ORD Studies VH: Applications to Problems of Absolute Configuration (170), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photos from "ORD Studies VII" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ORD Studies VII: α,β —Unsaturated Ketones and Solvent Effects (182), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photos from ORD Studies VHI" " (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ORD Studies XI: Structure et Dispersion Rotatoire (199), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Recent Advances in the Chemistry of Steroid Transformation: First National Medicinal Chemistry Symposium, June 1958 (214b), (includes photos), 1958 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Steroids CXXXVII: Synthesis of a New Class of Potent Cortical Hormones, 6α, 9α-Difluoro-16«. Hydroxyprednisolone and its Acetonide (288), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ORD Studies XLVII: Application of ORD to Organic Chemistry (328), 1960-1961 (includes negatives) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application of Optical Rotatory Disperson Studies to Problems in Natural Products Chemistry (1960 IUPAC Symposium) (Australia) (330) (includes photo) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ORD Studies: Octant Rule (339), 1961, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ORD Studies: Octant Rule (339)1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mass Spectrometry (MSSSP) I: Steroids, Ketones by c. Djerassi and H. Bodzikiewicz (362), 1962 (includes photos) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ORD LXXIV: Octant Rule I by C. Djerassi and KLyne, (392), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ORD LXXVIH: Comparative Studies of Circular Dichroism and Rotatory Dispersion Curves; Sulfur-Containing Chramophones byDjerassi, Wolf and Bunnenberg (396), 1962 (includes negatives) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mass Spectrometric Investigations in the Steroid, Terpenoid and Alkaloid Fields by Djerassi XXV (417), 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photos from "Mass Spectrometric Investigations...XXV" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP XXXII: Pentacyclic Triterpenes byH. Budzikiewicz, Wilson and Djerassi (434), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photos and negatives from “MSSSP XXXII" (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ORD Studies XCIV: Solvation by Moscowitz, Welman, Djerassi (435), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photos, figures, and negatives from "CRD Studies XCIV" (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - XLVI: Applications of ORD and CD in Stereochemistry (Centenary Lecture) by Carl Djerassi (476), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photos and figures from "XLVI: Applications of ORD and CD..." (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP LVII: Isotope labeling and Mass Spectrometry of Natural Products by Carl Djerassi (477), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photos and figures from “MSSSP LVII" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ORD Studies XCVEH: The Conformation of the 17-Acetyl Group in Steroids and Its Correlation with Variable-Temperature Circular Dichroism by Keith M. Wellman and Carl Djerassi (485), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "ORD Studies XCVIII" (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ORD Studies XCIX: Superposed Multiple Cotton Effects on Saturated Ketones and their Significance in the Circular Dichroism Measurements of (-) Menthone, K.M. Wellman, P.A. Laur, W. S. Briggs, A. Mbscowitz and C. Djerassi (486), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "ORD Studies XCIX" (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ORD Studies C: Variable Temperature CD Studies of Ring-Conformational and Rotational Equilibria in Cyclohexanones by K.M. Wellman, W.S. Briggs, C. Djerassi (487), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "ORD Studies C" (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP LXV: Synthesis and Fragmentation Behavior of 15-Keto Steroids; Importance of Interatomic Distance in the Mclafferty Rearrangement by C. Djerassi, G. von Mutzenbecher, J. Fajkos, D.H. Williams and H. Budzikiewicz (494), 1964 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Magnetic Circular Dichroism (MCD) Studies: A Preliminary Report by D.A. Schooley, E. Bunnenberg, C. Djerassi (498), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from “MCD Studies" (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - MSSSP LXVII: Retro-Diels-Alder Reaction Organic Molecules under Electron Impact by H. Budzikiewicz, J.I. Braumann and C. Djerassi (509), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from “MSSSP LXVII" (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Recent Applications of Mass Spectrometry in Steroid Chemistry by Djerassi, Budzikiewicz and Wilson (515), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photos and negatives from "Recent Applications..." (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ORD Studies CIV: low Temperature Circular Dichroism Behavior of Various Chromophoric Derivatives of Alcohols and Amines by W. Scott Briggs and Carl Djerassi (533), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "ORD Studies CIV" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Steroid Oral Contraceptives by C. Djerassi (546), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CVI: Occurrence of Alkyl and Aryl Rearrangements in the Fragmentation of Some Organic Carbonates by P. Brown and C. Djerassi (560), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Photos and negatives from "MSSSP CVI" (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Terpenoids LVII: Mass Spectral and Nuclear Magnetic Resonance studies of Pentacyclic Triterpene Hydrocarbons by J. Karliner and C. Djerassi (561), 1966 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - MCD studies II: Preliminary Results with some Aromatic Compounds by D.A. Schooley, E. Bunnenberq, C. Djerassi (574), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "MCD studies II" (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ORD studies CIX: An octant Rule for the Azide Chromophore by C. Djerassi, A. Moscowitz, K. Ponsold, et. ale (580), 1966 (includes negatives) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - MSSSP XC: Mass Spectra of Linear Di-, Tri-, and Tetrapyrrolic compounds by A.H. Jackson, G.W. Kenner, H. Budzildewicz, C. Djerassi and J. M. Wilson (581), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - ORO studies CVII: Factors Governing the Relative stability of Hydrindanones; synthesis of 17-Alkyl-15-Keto steroids by A.R. Van Horn and C. Djerassi (584), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - MSSSP CXXVIII: Further studies on the Mass Spectromoetry of 15-Keto steroids by A.R. Van Horn and C. Djerassi (586), 1967 (includes photo and negative) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CXXV: Mass Spectrometry of Some Trllnethylsilyl Ethers by J. Diekman and C. Djerassi (589), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CKXVI: synthesis and Fragmentation Behavior of Deuterim labeled 17-Keto steroids by L. Tokes, R.T. LaLonde and C. Djerassi (590), 1967 (includes photo and negative) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP CKXVII: Synthesis and Fragmentation Behavior of Deuterium labeled 20-Keto steroids by Laszlo Tokes, R.T. LaLonde, C. Djerassi (591), 1966 (includes photo and negative) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - MSSSP CXXXID:: Rearrangements by P. Brown and C. Djerassi (595), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - MSSSP CXXXID:: Rearrangements by P. Brown and C. Djerassi (595), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CXXX: Migratory Aptitudes by P. Brown and C. Djerassi (594), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of organic Molecules by C. Djerassi (597), no date (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Photos and figures from "Electron Impact... " (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Some Applications of Newer Physical Methods in the steroid Field by C. Djerassi (598), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "Some Applications…" (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP CXXXII: Aryl and Alkyl Rearrangements by R.L.N. Harris, F. Komitsky and C. Djerassi (602), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Macrolide Antibiotics XV: Nystatin--'The structure of Aglycone by M. ldeda, M. SUzuki and C. Djerassi (604), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CXXXVI: Primary Hydrogen Isotope Effects in the McLafferty Rearrangement by J .K. Macleod and C. Djerassi (605), 1967 (includes photo and negative) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CXXXVII: Examples of Interaction of Remote Functional Groups after Electron Impact by M. Green and C. Djerassi (606), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP CXL: Competitive McLafferty Rearrangements in Bifunctional Compounds by J. K. Macleod and C. Djerassi (611), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - MSSSP CXLV: Factors Governing the Preferential Loss of Small vs Large Radicals in Ketones, Schiff Bases and Ethers by W. Carpenter, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (613), 1967 (includes photos) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Alkaloid Studies LVIII: The Alkaloids of Seven Aspidosperna Species by R.R. Arndt, S.H. Brown, N.C. Ling, P. Roler, C. Djerassi, J.M. Ferreira, B. Gilbert, et. Al (615), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CXLI: The Electron Impact Induced Fragmentations and Rearrangements of Trimethylsilyl Ethers, Amines and Sulfides by J. Diekmann, J.B. Thompson and C. Djerassi (616), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CXXXVIII: Fragmentation Processes of Some Thiocarbonyl Compounds on Electron Impact by A.M. Duffield, C. Djerassi and J. Sandröm (6l9), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Problem of Establishing Centers of Excellence for Basic Research in Developing Countries by C. Djerassi (620), 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - MSSSP CXLIV: Unusual Fragmentation in Low Voltage Spectra of Aliphatic Ketones by W. Carpenter, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (621), 1967 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - MSSSP CXLVI: Mass Spectrometric Fragmentations of Some sterols by S.G. Wyllie and C. Djerassi (622), 1967 (includes photo and negative) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP CXLIX: Ring Expansion by M. Marx and C. Djerassi (623), 1967-1968 (includes photo and Negative) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Homogenous Hydrogenation of Steroids by W. Voelter and C. Djerassi (624), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - ORD Studies CXI: The Octant Rule and Equatorial Alkoxycarbonyl and Carboxyl Groups; Synthesis of Optically Active Adamantanones by W.S. Briggs, M. SUChy, and C. Djerassi (626), 1967-1968 (includes Photo) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CLIII: Electron Impact Promoted Fragmentation of n-Alkyl Cyanides by W,. Carpenter, Y. Sheikh, A.M. Dlffield and C. Djerassi (628), 1968 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Some Applications of Magnetic Circular Dichroism and Optical Rotatory Disperson Measurements by B. Briat and C. Djerassi (630), 1968 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Pyrolysis of the Epimeric df and 2-d-2-Methyl-cyclohexyl-S-methyl Xanthates and Acetates by W. Scott Briggs and C. Djerassi (633), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - MSSSP CLIX: The Question of Ring Expansion in the Electron Impact Induced Fragmentation of Aromatic Amines by Robertson, Marx and C. Djerassi (634), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Alkaloid studies LIX: The structure and Absolute Configuration of Vallesamidine by S.H. Brown, C. Djerassi and P.J. Simpson (636), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rearrangement Reactions in Organic Mass Spectometry by C. Djerassi (642), 1967 (includes photos) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CLXI: Elucidation of the Course of the Characteristic Ring D Fragmentation of steroids by L. Tokes, G. Jones and C. Djerassi (646), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from ''MSSSP CLXI" (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - MSSSP CLXVII: Long Range Hydrogen Transfers in Mass Spectometry by R. Brandt and C. Djerassi (652), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from ''MSSSP CLXVII" (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - ORD studies CXII: Thiosteroids ORD and CD of Steroidal Thiocyanates by Lightner, Djerassi, Takeda, et.al. (654), 1968 (includes negatives) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - MSSSP CLXX: A Study of the Effect of Ring Size in Reciprocal Hydrogen Transfers by G. Eadon and C. Djerassi (663), 1968-1969 (includes photo and Negative) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference I: The Number of Possible Organic Compounds; Acyclic Structures Containing C, H, and 0 by J. Lederberg, G.L. Sutherland, B.G. Buchanan, E.A. Feigenbamn, A.V. Robertson, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (664), 1969 (includes photo and Negatives) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference II: Interpretation of Low Resolution Mass Spectra of Ketones by A.M. Duffield, A. V. Robertson, C. Djerassi, B.G. Buchanan, G.L. Sutherland, E.A. Feigenbaum and J. Lederberg (665), 1969 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - MSSSP CLXXI: Factors Governing the Preferential Loss of Small vs. Large Radicals in the -Fission of Aliphatic Amines by C.A. Brown, A.M. Duffield, C. Djerassi (668), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - MSSSP CLXXVII: Application of Ion Cyclotron Resonance to the structure Elucidation of the C H 0: Ion Formed in the Double Mclafferty Rearrangement by G. Eaden, J. Diekmann and C. Djerassi (671), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "MSSSP CLXXVII" (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - MSSSP CLXXVI: Androstanes by L. Tokes and C. Djerassi (673), 1969 (includes negatives) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - MSSSP CLXX: Oxygen Rearranqement and Fragmentation Reactions after Electron Impact on 4-Hydroxy- and 4-Alkoxy-1-Decalones by R.T. Gray, M. Ikeda and C. Djerassi (682), 1969 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence III: Interpretations of Low Resolution Mass Spectra of Aliphatic Ethers by G. Schroll, A.M. Duffield, C.Djerassi, B.G. Buchanan, G.L. Sutherland, E.A. Feigenbuam and J. Lederberg (683), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Alkaloids LXII: X-ray Crystallographic Structure Determination of Dichotine HydrobrOmide by N. Ling, C. Djerassi and P.G. Simpson (686), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CXC: Electron Impact Induced Triple Hydrogen Migration in Vinyl Alkyl Ethers by M. Katoh and C. Djerassi (687), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ORD studies CXVII: Absolute Configurational Assignments of Some Aromatic Carboxylic Acids by Circular Dichroism Measurements by G. Barth, W. Voelter, H.S. Mosher, E. Bunnenberg and C. Djerassi (688), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "ORD Studies CXVII" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Terpenoids LXV: Chemical Studies of Marine Invertebrates VI by B. Tursch, R. Cloetens and C. Djerassi (689), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - MSSSP CLXXXII: Investigations in the 10-Phenyl-2-Decalone system: The Synthesis and Electron Impact Promoted Phenyl Migration of trans-10-Phenyl-Δ3-2-Octalone by R.T. Gray and C. Djerassi (690), 1969-1970 (includes photo and Negative) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - MCD XI: Investigation of Some Adenosine Cyclonucleosides by Elder, Bunnenberg, Djerrasi, Ikehara, Voelter (691), 1970 (includes photo and Negatives) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Demonstration of a Biogenetically Unprecedented Side Chain in the Marine Sterol, Gorgosterol by Hale, Djerassi, Weinheimer and Scheuer (692), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - MSSSP CIXXXIV: Charge Localization in Fragment Ions of Amino Ketones and Esters by J. Cable, G.W. Adelstein, J. Gore and C. Djerassi (693), 1969 (includes photos) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - MSSSP CIXXXV: Effect of the Phenyl Group in the Mass Spectra of trans-10-Phenyl-2-decalone and trans-10-phenyl-decalin by R.T. Gray and C. Djerassi (694), 1969-1970 (includes photo and negative) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - MSSSP CLXXXI: Further studies of Remote Group Interactions after Electron Impact in 4-substituted cyclohexanones by R.T. Gray, R.J. Spangler and C. Djerassi (695), 1969-1970 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - MSSSP in Structural and Sterochemical Problems CLXXXVIII: The Electron Impact Induced Behavior of Branched Ketones and Fsters…Rearrangements by Eadon and Djerassi (696), 1969-1970 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - MSSSP CXCII: Skeletal Rearrangement in the Fragmentation of Plenyl Azide by P.D. Woodgate and C. Djerassi (697), 1970 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - MSSSP CLXXXVII: A study of Skeletal Rearrangements in Chromans by Combined 13 C-Deuterium Tahel.ing by J.R. Trudell, S.D. Sample and C. Djerassi (698), 1970 (includes photo and negative) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Tarpenoids LXVI: Simultaneous Functionalization of the C-18 and C-l9 Angular Methyl Groups in llB-yl-Acetate by Lead Tetraacetate-Iodine Oxidation by P. Roller and C. Djerassi (699), 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - MCD studies X: Investigation of Some Carbonyl Compounds by G. Barth, E. Bunnenberq, C. Djerassi, D. Elder and R. Records (701), no date (includes photos and negatives) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Side Chain Transformations and Deuterium Labeling in the Steroidal Sapogenin Series by Faul, Failli and C. Djerassi (702), 1970 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Terpenoids LXVII: Chemical Studies of Marine Invertebrates VII: Interconversion... by P. Roller, B. TUrsch and C. Djerassi (703), 1969-1970 (includes photo and negative) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Alkaloid studies LXIV: The crystal structure and Absolute Configuration of (-) 17-I-Methy1-Aspidodispermine-Nb-Hydrobromide by Ling and Djerassi (704), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - MSSSP CXCI: Applications of Mass Spectrometry in the Steroid Field by C. Djerassi (705), 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Photos, figures and negatives from "MSSSP CXCI" (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The Structure and Absolute Configuration of the Marine Sterol Gorgosterol by Hale, Ling and Djerassi (707), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - MSSSP CLXXXIX: Electron Impact Induced Fragmentations and Rearrangements of Aloxycyclohexanol Trimethylsilyl Ether and Alkoxycyclohexyltrimethylsilanes by Gray, Diekman and C. Djerassi (708), 1969-1970 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP CXCIII: On the combined Hydroxyl and Water Loss in Nitrophenylhydrazones by R.J. Liedtke, A.M. Duffield and C. Djerassi (709), 1970 (includes photo and negative) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - MSSSP CXCV: The Structure of the [C6H6O]± Ion in the Spectrum of Phenyl Alkyl Ethers by P. Woodgate and C. Djerassi (710), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - MSSSP CXCIV: The Mass Spectrometric Fragmentations of Steroidal Sapogenins by Faul and Djerassi (711), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Photos and negatives from "MSSSP CXCIV" (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Alkaloid studies LXII: the Constitution and Chemistry of Dichotine and ll-Methoxydichotine by N.C. Ling and C. Djerassi (712), 1970 (includes photos) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference VI: Approach to a General Method of Interpreting Low Resolution Mass Spectra with a Computer by Buchs, Delfino, Duffield, Djerassi, Buchanan, Feigenbaum and Ledelberg (713), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Application of Ion Cyclotron Resonance to the Structure Elucidation of the C_H_O Ion Formed in the Double McLafferty Rearrangement by Eadon, Diekman and C. Djerassi (714), 1970 (includes photos and Negative) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - ORD Studies CXVIII: Aliphatic C-Nitroso Compounds by N.D. Vietmeyer and C. Djerassi (715), 1970 (includes Photos) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference IV: Saturated Amines Diagnosed by their Low Resolution Mass Spectra and Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectra by Buchs, Duffield, C. Djerassi, Schroll, Delfino, Buchanan, sutherland, Feigenbaum and Lederberg (716), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photos and negatives from "Applications of AI... " (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - MSSSP CXCVII: Electron Impact Induced Functional Group Interaction in 4-Benzyloxycyclohexyl Trimethylsilyl Ether by Woodgate, Gray, Djerassi (717), 1970 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - MSSSP CXCVIII: A study of the Fragmentation Processes of Same α, B-Unsaturated Aliphatic Ketones by Sheikh, Duffield and C. Djerassi (718), 1970 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Applications of Artificial Intelligence V: An Approach to the Computer Generation of Cyclic Structures; Differentiation Between all the Possible Isomeric ketones of Composition C6H10O by Y.M. Sheikh, A. Buchs, A.B. Delfino, G. Schroll, A.M. Duffield, C. Djerassi, B.G. Buchanan, G.L. Sutherland, E.A. Feigenbaum, and J. Lederberg (719), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - MSSSP CC: A Study of the Fragmentation Processes of Some Pyrilium Salts by A.M. Duffield, C. Djerassi and A.T. Balaban (721), 1970 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Acansterol: A Cyclopropane Containing Marine Sterol from Acanthaster Planei by Y.M. Sheikh, C. Djerassi and B.M. Tursch (722), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - MCD Studies XII: The Determination of Tryptophan in Proteins (726), 1971 (includes photos and negatives) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - MSSSP CCV: The Mass Spectra of Trimethylisilyl Ethers of Phenols and the Importance of Neighboring Group Participation in Fragmentation by G.G. Smith and C. Djerassi (727), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - MSSSP CXCIX: Contrasting Fragmentations of Singly and Doubly Charged I-, m- and. p- Hydroxyalkylphenones and their Trimethylsilyl Ethers by G.G. Smith and C. Djerassi (728), 1970-1971 (includes photos and Negatives) (Box 10, Folder 14)